# PAUL MURPHY

Address: Co. Meath **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/TestCodeRefactor/

**Mobile:** 087 9262302 **GitHub:** https://github.com/Mur3ph

> **Email:** paulmurphymainstreet@gmail.com

A motivated and passionate software tester/ developer, and quality with experience working in banking, finance and start-up companies. In my next role I'd like to learn more in-depth knowledge of software testing on web, API and mobile applications to enhance further and widen testing skills.

### IT COMPETENCIES

- Java: (Good), C#.NET: (Basic/Intermediate), JavaScript: (Basic), SQL, HTML JSP, Razor, Thymeleaf, JEE, NET (Basic/Intermediate), XML, JSON, Apache Tomcat, Windows IIS
- JUnit, Manual, Debugging, Fiddler, Postman, Regression, Integration, Agile(Scrum)
- Eclipse, Microsoft Visual Studio, Intellij, SQL Server, SQL Developer, GIT
- Personal Use: Spring(Basic/Intermediate), Selenium (Basic), TestNG(Basic), JMeter

### **CAREER HISTORY**

**ORACLE** 2016-Present

Application Analyst/Support (Full-time: September 2016 - Present)

**Role Played** Monitoring, Testing, Analyse, Reducing Risk, Automation, & Maintaining SEPA

Payments Applications, and business requests.

**Brief:** 

Analysis and investigate root cause of issues/failures/bugs Using SQL scripts for daily work – SQL Developer Searching logs and traces for errors via UNIX Monitoring application/database/MQ servers and business app.

Wrote an automation alerts using Java

Support in app. changes, upgrades, runbook, meetings Prioritizing time critical tasks with multiple teams across entire bank

**Technologies:** Oracle, Java, SQL, Linux, Excel, Manual Testing and Analyse

### **DUNRAVEN SYSTEMS LTD**

2015-2016

Application Developer (Full-time: May 2015 - August 2016)

**Role Played** Maintaining, Testing, Developing and Deploying various web, mobile and desktop applications using .NET eco-system.

**Brief:** 

- Designed User Interface for Web and Mobile application Developed Web Service, and Desktop app., with GUI

- Developed Web Service, and Desktop app., with GUI
  Developed map feature to visualize and monitor customer data
  Developed weather functionality via third party API
  Maintained and Supported legacy system for customer requirements
  Refactored legacy system while adding further functionality daily
  Developed, Maintained and Updated SQL Server database
  Documented development progress, releases, versions and changes
  Tested all releases and changes before deployment
  Deploy applications live to Windows IIS production server

**Technologies:** NET, C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Razor, MVC5, MS SQL Server, XML, JSON, GIT,

Manual Testing, Unit, Regression, Fiddler API Testing, Cross Browser Testing &

debugging, Visual Studio, NuGet manager

REVENUE 2015

Application Developer (Contract: October 2014 – May 2015)

**Role Played** Developing, Deploying, Testing and maintaining application for business

**Brief:** • Migrating and Upgrading Confluence

• Rewriting a Java application to accept a yearly license update through an Interpreter (JVM) argument, using a "–D" command line script (Automation).

 Making changes to applications for business users by reducing code duplication. Testing any changes made and finally deploying the application.

**Technologies:** Eclipse, Java, MySQL, Linux (Redhat), FileZilla, Continues integration(Jenkins),

Version Control(SVN and CVS repositories), Alfresco, JUnit Testing, Regression Testing, Integration Testing, Agile/Scrum, Apache-(Tomcat, Solr – Lucene etc.)

#### HOUGHTON MIFFIN HARCOURT

2014

Application Developer (Summer Internship: June - September)

Role Played Bug fixes, Test Coverage, Unit Testing, Debugging, Daily Stand-up, and Code

Reviews

**Technologies** Java, MQ, MySQL, Eclipse, Junit, Web Services

PROMETRIC 2013

UX and Manual Testing (College Experience: no pay (Jan.- April))

ATTENDED COLLEGE 2009-2014
J&P CONSTRUCTION 1998-2008

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

#### Attended: Dundalk Institute of Technology (DKIT)

2009-2014

Honours Degree in Commercial Computing Second Class Honours 2.1 September 2014
Ordinary Degree in Software Development Second Class Honours 2.1 September 2013

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE & CAUSES**

#### MENTOR - CODER DOJO

Educating young minds to how a computer program works is a pleasure. A great way to learn is to teach. We start by teaching them the basic problem solving skills required using tools like HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

#### **INTERESTS - HOBBIES**

Constantly learning with courses online, blogs, articles and developers, reading (currently reading Java Network Programming), Enjoy teaching nieces coding, nephews no interest in coding  $\odot$ , Tennis